[Music]
so
this obviously for me brings up thoughts
of when we talk about whistleblowing
about julian assange and
what he's going through right now and
to me i've viewed this for a long time
that if we
actually do extradite julian assange and
try him for
espionage we're basically ending our
first amendment
like that's without a doubt this is like
yes without a doubt and shame on the
washington post the new york times
the wall street journal and others for
not leaping to his defense because
they're next
yeah if julian assange is convicted he's
going to be tried in the eastern
district of virginia if he's extradited
if he's convicted then every working
journalist in america is going to be a
target
yeah it's extremely scary and it's and
not only are they not covering it it's
almost like they're covering it up
i i have noticed that for years i've
been very well versed in what's going on
with julian i've been following this for
probably eight or nine years now
and it's just out of control what's
going on with him and it's similar to
what happened to you in that
what they're really wanting to get him
for is not how this all ended up getting
wrapped up for him he ended up i mean
they charged him with like sexual
assaults that were bogus and
like ridiculous thoughts yeah that's the
strategy uh they they
they do that now it's a strategy that
they've developed
after after i was arrested and tom drake
was arrested and
and uh chelsea manning and ed snowden
they developed this
this policy where they um will charge
you with sexual
impropriety of some sort look at people
like matt de hart for example
um or the vault 7 whistleblower what
they'll do
is charge you with let's say child porn
or or sexual assault in the case of
julian
and then when they come up to
trial they drop it and they say oh
oh no our bad there was no child porn on
the computer
we made a mistake that's what they did
with matt to heart
they incarcerated him because they said
they found child porn on his computer
there was no child porn
completely made up completely and
totally made up
now they're telling us that that we
should believe that there's child porn
on the vault seven
whistleblowers hard drive or that julian
raped two swedish women
and then ah now that falls apart but you
know he's a really bad guy
otherwise you know he leaked all this
information i still can't figure out how
you can charge
somebody that's not a us citizen um
under the espionage act nor do
i isn't that i mean is it julian's an
australian national
um and so how can he be i mean as far
and i'm an attorney so i look at this
and i'm like how does he have any
responsibility yes to protect our
country
even if it even if he was doing what
they said i mean why is he
even why why do we have any say so about
what julian assange does
yeah that's right he's under no legal
obligation to protect national defense
information
none none whatsoever in fact the
journalist
he's won journalistic awards and that's
why i say
if he's convicted then every national
security
reporter in america is going to be a
target you know interesting
enough too as you mentioned julian is an
australian uh citizen
i've given many interviews to australian
journalists
about julian and his case and no one
ever
asks me about the efficacy of a
prosecution using the
espionage act it's like nobody's
thinking about it nobody's talking about
it
he should never have been charged in the
first place now chelsea
manning was charged with multiple counts
of espionage
that's different that's different yes
that's different
and and the fbi and the cia maintain
that julian solicited the
information and then assisted chelsea
and hacking into the system
there's no evidence that that ever
happened no i mean i mean they they held
her for how long trying to get her to
basically say
oh assange is who guided me to do this
because
what they want and she's tough she
didn't
she's that's another one that i just
i feel like as a citizen in this country
we
can't pay her back enough like i i don't
know
how people can have anything but
admiration
for for her and yet mad respectfully
manning
i i know chelsea relatively well not not
very very well not like you know tom
drake or ed snowden or some of the
others
but um but chelsea is disarming
because she's very soft-spoken
she's very down-to-earth she's not an
imposing figure in
any way and then she is tougher
than 99.9 of the men that i know
yeah will not buckle to the justice
department i have crazy respect for that
most people would would just cave if
they say look
just testify against julian
or you go to prison her response is
lock me up yeah i'm not saying a word
and she
puffs it out until the bitter end it's
crazy so what finally allowed
why did they finally release her this
time the the only reason they released
her there was a lot of public pressure
it wasn't the public pressure that got
her released
it was the fact that was two things one
the judge
finally came to an understanding that
she really was not going to testify
period she just wasn't going to testify
and the other thing
was that um they the prosecutors were
not going to add any more charges
against julian for which they would need
chelsea's information to support
and so finally the judge said just let
her out it's just unbelievable but
without that they really don't have
anything which then
i still don't understand how they're
going to have a legitimate case against
him
no um there's got to be
one juror out there who is going to
have the the fortitude to stand up and
say this i hope so
you know what though i'll tell you a
little another little anecdote about my
own case
my best friend um my best friend's wife
has an uncle who happened to be
o.j simpson's jury consultant
that's random okay totally random
washington's a very small town
yeah so god bless him he flew up here
from dallas we got him a security
clearance he went through all the
the paperwork i had 15 000 pages of
classified documents that that we were
using for my defense
and then we all get to get got together
for a meeting at the attorney's
conference room and he said look
if this were any other district in
america
besides the eastern district of virginia
he said i'd say let's go for it we're
going to win this thing you haven't done
anything wrong
but the eastern district of virginia
they call it the espionage court for a
reason because
no nationals no national security
defendant
has ever won a case there so he said
look at your jury your jury would be
made up of people
from the cia the pentagon the
fbi the department of homeland security
and
a myriad of intelligence community
contractors
or their relatives he said you don't
stand a chance
yeah just take the deal and start
the deal yeah no and we railroad people
for everything all the time so it's not
it's
not even remotely surprising to me and
i'm coming from a criminal defense
background this is not
this is not uncommon by by any stretch
what can what can we do to
for whistleblowers what because
obviously there's
beyond blackballing and ghosting from
mainstream media
and you know independent media does a
decent job i mean i
you know obviously i've seen you on
shows and i've seen good coverage of
julian and there are
things out there but is there anything
you know or think of that we can do
so that more people can understand
what's going on here
that's a very tough question it's far
tougher than it sounds
um and people ask me all the time and i
don't really have a perfect
answer so i'll tell you what i what i
generally tell people
it's incumbent upon all of us to
constantly be
out there talking about these issues
this show
this topic is a public service people
need to hear
these issues because they're important
to all of us they're really critical
number two we have to ride our elected
officials
we have to call them and write them and
email them and demand
that they support national security
whistleblowers we have to demand
real congressional oversight of
organizations like the cia
and nsa and the fbi and the rest of them
yeah
otherwise just by their very nature they
run rampant
roughshod over our civil liberties and
let's let me let me explain to people
that
because a lot of people listen to this
are probably newbies to a lot of this
stuff
and that is what we refer to as the deep
state for
for people that um are listening when i
say deep state we're talking about these
executive branch federal agencies that
have no accountability to
the american people and basically they
have been in charge for a very long time
this goes back
60 years already at least with with
those in terms of
just complete running amok and no
president
that in my lifetime has even attempted
to really reign that in
yeah no president and you made a point
when we first
started the show first started talking
uh that it doesn't matter if it's a red
administration or a blue administration
you know george
w bush killed four people with the use
of a drone in his last
month as president barack obama killed
people with drones in his last month as
president
so this isn't exclusive to the
republicans the republicans aren't the
ones who decided they're going to be
jerks to whistleblowers
and they're going to use the espionage
act this is most certainly
bipartisan in nature you know i i gave
an interview to a to a chilean newspaper
the week that donald trump was elected
president and they they interviewed me
they interviewed tom drake from nsa
and they interviewed ed snowden and um
and they asked all of us if we thought
things would be
better under donald trump or worse under
donald trump for national security
whistleblowers
i foolishly said that i was cautiously
optimistic because they couldn't
possibly get any worse
than they were under barack obama never
say that i
it was a stupid mistake because of
course things got worse
almost instantaneously yeah we have
reality winners serving five and a half
years
uh she's nsa whistleblower we have terry
albury
uh who actually is getting out of within
a week from today
um the fbi whistleblower uh and there
are we know
from from uh jeff sessions the former
attorney general and his big mouth that
there are 123 active
national security investigations going
on right now so it's
far worse than barack obama yeah the
sentences are longer
than they were under barack obama so how
do you
how would you foresee what do you
anticipate that we're going to see under
a joe biden administration
regarding some of this and our foreign
policy um
obviously i see him as obama's point 2.0
right out of my mouth i see kamala as
hillary
in a kamala suit yep um
the career prosecutor yeah imagine the
thousands of lives that she
ruined by sending people uh to prison
for long stretches for having you know
personal use drugs so you don't have any
high hopes for the
for the biden administration for
anything no i don't